Neil Hart

San Francisco Bay Area, Northern California USA

SUMMARY

Neil is a Partner in PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP's (PwC) Strategic Technology Advisory practice. He has over sixteen years of international experience at C-level and has served the top management and IT management in a large number of Global 500 enterprises, particularly in the communications, media and high-tech and financial services sectors.

Prior to working with PwC, Neil led Ernst & Young's Technology Consulting practice on the West Coast for Financial Services clients and before that led their Accenture's Technology Consulting practice on the West Coast. He previously held IT Strategy leadership positions for Accenture in Israel, the Netherlands and London. Over the past decade, Neil has built three consulting practices from the ground up into multi-million dollar businesses. His clients are among the most recognized names in their respective sectors.

E-Mail:

resume@hart.im

Neil's recent client experience includes restructuring the businesses and operations of industry leading companies to address changing market dynamics; from traditional to digital businesses, the emergence of cloud technologies, multi-vendor management and the ability to act with the agility of a start-up.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Current:	PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP, Partner, Strategic Technology Advisory
2013 – 2015:	Ernst & Young, Strategic Technology Advisory Practice Lead, Financial Services (West Coast)
2008 – 2013:	Accenture USA, Managing Director (Partner), Technology Consulting Practice Lead, Media & High-Tech (West Coast)
2008 – 2010:	Accenture Israel, Technology Consulting Practice Lead
2000 – 2008:	Accenture London, Strategy Senior Manager
1999 – 2000:	Webreaction Ltd (Internet Consultancy), Director
1999:	Genesys - The Travel Technology Consultancy, Technology Consultant

SELECTED CLIENT EXPERIENCE

Digital Strategy Global Insurance	Engagement partner developing a strategy for how this global insurance organization would address the business opportunities and competitive threats that digital introduces. Specifically around their future customer engagement model, big data driven business insight, rapid adaptability of their business processes and an engagement model for working with external partners.
Cloud Strategy Leading Global Enterprise Software Developer	Engagement partner developing a commercial model and strategy with two objectives. The first, to deploy this organization's own cloud platform internally and at what pace to migrate from traditiona infrastructure. The second, to develop a go-to-market proposition for how they could replicate this model for other enterprises and thereby increase market adoption of this platform.
IT Spend Assessment Leading Global Enterprise Software Developer	Engagement lead performing a spend assessment of this \$1.5Bn+ spend IT organization. Directly reporting to the CIO and his IT Management, the assessment focused on realigning IT with the business agenda and reducing wasted expenditure.
Technology Strategy – Digital Distribution Major Video Gaming Developer / Publisher	Developed the technology strategy and roadmap to facilitate the transition from a packaged goods based business to a future focused on digital distribution and services. Included the sourcing strategy and operating model to enable this strategic vision.
eCommerce Transformation Market Leading US Entertainment Co.	Engagement Lead mobilizing an eCommerce focused transformation program, which included a partner and organization change management component as well as a full-scale systems re-platform Neil led the initial sale to this client, with a total program value, to Accenture, in the tens of millions of dollars.
IT Transformation Largest Israeli Bank	Sponsored directly by the Bank's Chairman, CEO and CIO, Neil led an IT Strategy focused on the IT organisation structure and operations to reduce cost, regain business trust and reduce operational failures. Neil led the subsequent 18 month transformation.

IT Spend Benchmark Major US Operator (Telecommunications)	Engagement lead performing a benchmark of this \$1Bn+ spend IT organization. Working with the organization SVPs and reporting directly to the CIO and CFO.
IT Strategy African Telco Group	Engagement lead evaluating the operating performance of the technology divisions across multiple countries. The benefits from this study resulted in savings in the tens of millions of dollars.
Cost Reduction Strategy Global Investment Bank	Lead for a team identifying and quantifying potential cost saving initiatives. Initially set a target of \$40m, Neil's team identified more than \$100m of initiatives.
Operations Analysis Israeli Communications	Analysis of a major operational process underpinning a key revenue stream for this company. The findings recommended amendments to product and operations, to improve revenue generation and cost efficiencies.
IT Capability Assessment UK Retail Bank	Assessed the bank's capability for capturing business demand and effectively channelling it into the IT delivery process. Developed criteria for assessing when IT demand could be fulfilled by accelerated delivery methods.
IT Outsourcing Assessment Global Retail & Investment Bank	Lead for a project to assess the opportunities for IT outsourcing (target sourcing model, operating model, organisational model, and benefits assessment) within the CIO organisation. This project was originated and sold by Neil.
Transformation of Retained IT Organisation Global Retail & Investment Bank	Project lead transforming the operating model and processes for the retained component of an IT organisation whose application development and maintenance had been outsourced.
Operations Analysis UK Newspaper	Lead (sales and delivery) for a project analysing the operations of a newly commissions print facility. This analysis led to the deployment of a new IT unit.
Financial Modelling Video Games Manufacturer	Strategy development aimed at improved presence in the video games marketplace as a publisher and developer. Generation of a financial model, for presentation to the CFO, which supported our recommendations.
IT Transformation European Incumbent Telco	Lead for 38 individual projects (over 3 phases) designed to establish a new IT organisation. The new organisation operates a budget of more than €500m and employs more than 1,000 people.
EDUCATION	

University of Leeds: Communication Studies with Philosophy

1997 - 2000

BA (Hons) awarded with a 2(i) graded degree.

The Manchester Grammar School

1989 - 1996

- 3 A-Level's (A) Religion & Philosophy, (B) Politics, (B) English Literature.
- 2 Mathematics A/S modules.
- 10 GCSE's.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Social Projects: Neil was the chair of the restoration committee for a 1890's listed community building in London. The role included fundraising, community consultation and requirements management of this \$7m project.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.